Guide to the Otto Kinkeldey papers, 1902-1966.
Kinkeldey, Otto papers, 1902-1966.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Otto Kinkeldey papers, 1902-1966.
14-20-1000
Otto Kinkeldey, 1878-1966.
12.4 cubic ft.; 2 rolls.
Correspondence, manuscripts, music scores, photographs, programs, clippings, printed material.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Professional papers include correspondence pertaining to his professorship and librarianship at Cornell and as a visiting professor elsewhere. Personal papers include correspondence with friends and family in Germany.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of Music (1923-1927) and University Librarian (1930-1946), Cornell University.
CHRONOLOGY
1878 Born in New York City
1898 CCNY - A.B.
1898-1902 Organist and Choirmaster, Episcopal Chapel of the Incarnation, New York City
1900 NYU - M.A.
1902-1909 Student, University of Berlin and Royal Academic Institute for Church Music in Berlin
1906-1907 Research, Germany; Cataloging and describing the musical scores and books on music in the libraries of the central German states
1909 Ph.D. thesis: "Orgel und Klavier in der Music des 16. Jahrhunderts"
1909-1914 Instructor in organ amd music theory at University of Breslau
1909- Librarian of the Royal Academic Institute for Church Music
1910-1914 Lecturer in Music History in the Faculty of Philosophy (Breslau)
1914-1923 New York Public Library - Head of Division of Music
1914-1917 United States Army
1923-1927 Cornell University - Chairman, Department of Music; University Organist, Sage Chapel Choir Director
1927-1930 New York Public Library
1930-1946 Cornell University Librarian and Professor of Musicology
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Professional papers include correspondence pertaining to his professorship and librarianship at Cornell and as a visiting professor elsewhere (1946-1958); organizations include the American Council of Learned Societies, the American Musicological Society, and the Music Library Association; correspondents include Carl Becker, Stephen Vincent Benet, Morris Bishop, Lane Cooper, Walter Damrosch, Albert Einstein, Stephen A. McCarthy, William Sulzer, Oliver Strunk, Walter Toscanini, and Paul J. Weaver. Personal papers include correspondence with friends and family in Germany, especially after World War II when he aided many with Care packages; also, unpublished manuscripts, music scores, photographs, concert programs, clippings, and other printed material.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Kinkeldey, Otto, 1878-1966.; Becker, Carl Lotus, 1873-1945.; Benet, Stephen Vincent, 1898-1943.; Bishop, Morris, 1893-1973.; Cooper, Lane, 1875-1959.; Damrosch, Walter, 1862-1950.; Einstein, Albert, 1879-1955.; McCarthy, Stephen A. (Stephen Anthony), 1908-; Strunk, W. Oliver (William Oliver), 1901-; Sulzer, William, 1863-1943.; Toscanini, Walter, 1898-1971.; Weaver, Paul John, 1889-1946.; American Council of Learned Societies.; American Musicological Society.; Cornell University. Library.; Cornell University. Dept. of Music.; Music Library Association.
Subjects:
Music--Instruction and study.; Library science.; College teachers--United States.; Librarians--United States.
Places:
Germany--Social conditions--20th century.
Form and Genre Terms:
Scores.; Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Personal Papers, 1922-1966, preserved in original order, include family correspondence, buisness papers, photographs, post cards
Box 1
Series II. Alphabetical Files, 1924-1966, arranged alphabetically and chronologically by correspondent, organization, or subject, include correspondence, music manuscripts, programs, buisness papers, biographies, recommendations, photographs, war posters, post cards, newsclippings. Note - Hans Erdmann and Erdmann Guckle are the same person - filed under Erdmann
Boxes 1-6
Series III. Subject Files, 1922-1965, include correspondence, programs, lists, newsclippings, bibliographies related to work and organizations, arranged alphabetically and chronologically
Box 6
Series IV. Subject Files (individual)
Subseries A. American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1942-1962, includes correspondence, programs, announcements, pamphlets, reports re AAAS, arranged chronologically
Box 6
Subseries B. American Council of Learned Societies, 1926-1940, includes correpondence, minutes, agenda, announcements, re ACLS, arranged chronologically
Boxes 6-7
Subseries C. American Music Society, 1955, includes correspondence, bills, lists, papers, music re AMS, arranged chronologoically
Box 7
Subseries D. Berkeley, correspondence during 1954-1955, includes correspondence, small watercolor, minutes, bills, proof, print, arranged alphabetically, chronologoically
Box 7
Subseries E. Columbia University Press, 1932-1952, includes correspondence, newsclippings, telegrams, re Musicology Committee and advice on publications, arranged chronologoically
Box 7
Subseries F. Denton, 1951-1952, correspondence while at Denton, Texas, includes programs, reports, recommendation, arranged alphabetically, chronologoically
Box 7
Subseries G. German Papers (legal size folder), 1901-1910, include job recommendations, letters (copies), contracts, papers, certificates re Music Society, arranged chronologoically
Box 7
Subseries H. Harvard Summer, 1936-1941, includes correspondence, reports, constitution, list, announcements, postcards, arranged alphabetically, chronologoically
Box7
Subseries I. Harvard, 1947-1948, includes correspondence, instructions re teaching at Harvard summer session, arranged alphabetically, chronologoically
Box 7
Subseries J. Harvard, 1962, 1931-1962, includes correspondence, telegrams, roll sheets and grades, newsclippings re teaching at Harvard, and publications by Harvard University Press, arranged chronologoically
Box 7
Subseries K. Music Libraries Association, 1931-1965, includes correspondence, rules, lists, minutes, bulletins, by-laws, excerpts, cataloging code, drafts re MLA
Box 8
Subseries L. National Music Council; 1941-1944, 1950, includes correspondence, by-laws, reports, bulletins
Box 8
Subseries M. New York Public Library, 1963, includes correspondence, reports, acknowledgments
Box 8
Subseries N. Society for Ethnomusicology, 1955-1956, includes correspondence, programs, minutes, certificates of incorporation
Box 8
Subseries O. Texas I, 1948-1949, includes correspondence, announcements, minutes, programs, bulletins, article, newsclippings, invitations, review, telegrams
Box 8
Subseries P. Texas II, 1949-1950, includes correspondence, minutes, bulletins, programs, bills, outlines, lists, postcards, newsclippings, telegrams, arranged alphabetically, chronologoically
Box 8
Subseries Q. Urbana, correspondence during 1953-1954, includes correspondence, papers, contents, report, list notes, statement, arranged alphabetically, chronologoically
Box 8
Series V. Lecture notes, correspondence, bibliographic notes, pamphlets, programs, certificates, newsclippings; 1901-1926, 1953
Boxes 9-12
Series VI. Miscellaneous materials and material from a file; pamphlets, music scores (ms., engraved and printed), programs, correspondence, patent, lecture notes
Box 12
Series VII. Photographs, artifacts, memorabilia
Box 13
Series VIII. Diplomas and certificates
Mapcase Folder 1
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Personal Papers, 1922-1966
  Preserved in original order
  Include family correspondence, business papers, photographs, post cards
  - Family Correspondence, 1922-1953 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Carl Kinkeldey Estate, 1934-1936 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Carl W. Kinkeldey Estate, 1946, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Carl Kinkeldey Letters, 1930-1946 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Clara Kinkeldey Estate, 1934-1950 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Max Kinkeldey Letters, 1928, 1933-1953 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Max Kinkeldey Letters, 1954-1959 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Max Kinkeldey Letters, 1960-1966 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Series II. Alphabetical Files, 1924-1966
  Include correspondence, music manuscripts, programs, business papers, biographies, recommendations, photographs, war posters, post cards, news clippings.
  Arranged alphabetically and chronologically by correspondent, organization, or subject.
  Hans Erdmann and Erdmann Guckle are the same person - filed under Erdmann
  - Aarhus - Adams (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - African - Albion (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Aldrich (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Allen - American (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - American Piano - Anderson (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Andiron Club, 1926-1934 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Andiron Club, 1934-1942 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Andiron Club, 193-1964 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Andrews - Aronson (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Associated - Austin (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Authors Club (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Auto - Ayars (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Babaian - Barber (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Barbour (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Barenreiter-Verlang - Bauman (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Bayliss - Beckmann (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Beethoven - Beveridge (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Bibliogrpahical - Bizony (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Blaauw - Blume (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Board - Bottger (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Bodoin - Barzier (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Breitkopf and Hartel (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Breslau - Brown (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Bruck - Burnham (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Burns - Byzantine (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Cairns - California (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Campbell - Carapetyan (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - CARE (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Carlton - Catholic (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Cazden - Century (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Challis - Cincinnati (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - City College of New York (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Clark - Collis (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Columbia University (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Commin - Corn (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Cornell - Cornell University, 1923-1933 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Cornell University, 1934-1944 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Cornell University, 1945-1965 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Coupon - Cuyler (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Damrosch - Davis (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Davison - Dello (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Delphic - Diamant (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Dickinson (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Dictionary - Doyle (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Drinker - Dykema (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Earhart - Einstein (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Elkus - Endicott-Johnson (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Engel (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Englander - Evans (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Fahnestock - Fitch (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Flanders - Fox (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Frampton - Fuller (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Gabrilowitsch (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Gelrud (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - General Foods - Gleason (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Goldthwaite - Grant (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Gray - Group (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Grout - Gsellius (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Guggenheim (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Guglielmo - Guttman (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Haas - Hammond (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Handschin - Hazmuka (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Health - Heyer (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Hibberd (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Hickmann - Hirsch (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Hobart - Hymn (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - I (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Jack - Jenny (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Jeppesen - Johnson, Harold (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Johnson, H. Earle - Julliard (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Kaidin - Kensico (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Keogh - Koch (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Koestler (Kostler) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Kopfermann - Kuttner (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Ladenburg - Landshoff (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Lang (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Lange - Lee Higginson (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Leeser - Lewiston (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Library of Congress (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Library Journal - Loeb (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Lomax - Lundeberg (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Lutge (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Lutje - Lyman (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - MacArdle - Maguire (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Mailmann - Meyer-Reinach (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Mead - Meyer (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Meyer-Baer - Missouri (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Modern - Music Supervisors (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Music Teachers' National Association (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Music - Meyers (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Nabokoff - National (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Neisser - New York (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Newark - North Carolina (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - North Texas - Nussbaum (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Oberdoerffer - Olsson (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - O'Meara (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Organ - Parrish (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Parthenia - Pfatteicher (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Phi Beta - Phi Beta Kappa (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Phi Kappa Phi (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Phi Kappa Sigma (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Phi Mu Alpha - Pittsburgh (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Plamenac - Poladian (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Polemann - Priaulx (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Princeton (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Princeton Univrsity Bicentennial Conference (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Pro Muscia - Quarterly (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Radin - Reicher (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Reifsnider - Richmond (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Richtmyer - Rockefellar (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Rockefeller Fund (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Rockwell - Ryan (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Sabine - Schapiro (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Scheide - Scholes (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Schrade (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Schramm - Seeger (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Seery - Silver Burdett (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Simon (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Sinclair - Slovac (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Smith (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Social Security - South Orange (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Southern California - Starrett (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Stasse (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Stechert - Straus (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Strunk, W. Oliver (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Stuckenschmidt - Syracuse (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Tabb - Terry (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Texas (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Theremin - Travelers (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Treman - Typewriter (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Ulrich - United (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - University - Utley (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Vail - Vincent (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Vining - Vroman (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Waschmann - Wardman (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Washington - Wayne (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Waever - Welch (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Wellesz - Williston (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Wislon - WNYC (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Wolf - Women's (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Wood (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Woodcock - Zincograph (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Series III. Subject Files, 1922-1965
  Includes correspondence, programs, lists, news clippings, bibliographies related to work and organizations.
  Arranged alphabetically, then chronologically
  - A-B (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - C (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - D-J (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - K-M (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - O-P (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - R-Y (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Series IV. Subject Files (individual)
  - Subseries A. American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1942-1962
    Includes correspondence, programs, announcements, pamphlets, reports re AAAS
    Arranged chronologically
    - 1942-1962 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Subseries B. American Council of Learned Societies (ACLS), 1926-1958
    Includes correspondence, minutes, agenda, announcements
    - 1926, 1929, 1931-1934 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - 1935 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - 1936 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - 1937 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - 1938 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Ja. 1939-Apr. 1939 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - May 1939-Dec. 1939 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Jan. 1940-May 1940 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - June 1940-Dec. 1940 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - 1941-1943 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 1944 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Jan. 13, 1945: Committee on Encyclopedia of Music (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - 1945 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - 1946-1958 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Subseries C. American Music Society, 1955
    Includes correspondence, bills, lists, papers, music.
    - 1955, Joint Annual Meeting (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Subseries D. Berkeley, 1954-1955
    Includes correspondence, small watercolor, minutes, bills, proof, print.
    - A (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - B-G (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - H-L (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - M-P (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - R-W (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Subseries E. Columbia University Press, 1932-1952
    Includes correspondence, news clippings, telegrams, re Musicology Committee and advice on publications.
    - 1932-1934 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - 1935 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - 1936 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - 1937 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - 1938 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - 1939-1941 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - 1942-1952 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Subseries F. Denton (Denton, Texas), 1951-1952
    Includes programs, reports, recommendation.
    - A (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - B-G (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - H-L (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - M-R (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - S-W (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Subseries G. German Papers (legal size folder), 1901-1910
    Includes job recommendations, letters (copies), contracts, papers, certificates re Music Society.
    - 1901-1910 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Subseries H. Harvard Summer, 1936-1941
    Includes correspondence, reports, constitution, list, announcements, postcards.
    Arranged chronologically, then alphabetically.
    - 1936-1938 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - 1939-1942 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - 1940-1941, correspondence (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Subseries I. Harvard, 1947-1948
    Includes correspondence, instructions re teaching at Harvard summer session.
    - A-B (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - C (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - D-G (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - H-L (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - M-R (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - S-X (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Subseries J. Harvard, 1931-1962
    Includes correspondence, telegrams, roll sheets and grades, news clippings re teaching at Harvard, and publications by Harvard University Press.
    - 1931-1938 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - 1939-1946 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - 1947-1948 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Harvard Summer, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - 1949-1955 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - 1952-1962 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Harvard University Press, 1943-1954 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Subseries K. Music Libraries Association, 1931-1965
    Includes correspondence, rules, lists, minutes, bulletins, by-laws, excerpts, cataloging code, drafts re MLA.
    - 1931 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - 1932 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - 1933-1935 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - 1936-1938 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - 1939-1940 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - 1941 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - 1942-1950 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - 1951-1960 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - 1961-1965 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Subseries L. National Music Council, 1931-1944, 1950
    Includes correspondence, by-laws, reports, bulletins.
    - 1940 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Jan. 1941-Apr. 1941 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - May 1941-Dec. 1941 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Jan. 1942-May 1942 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - July 1942-Dec. 1942 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - 1943-1945 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Subseries M. New York Public Library, 1963, 1915-1950
    - 1915, 1927-1928 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - 1939-1963 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Subseries N. Society for Ethnomusicology, 1955-1956
    Includes correspondence, programs, minutes, certificates of incorporation.
    - Society for Ethnomusicology, 1955-1965 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Subseries O. Texas I, 1948-1949
    Includes correspondence, announcements, minutes, programs, bulletins, article, news clippings, invitations, review, telegrams.
    - A-B (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - C (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - D-G (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - H-K (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - L-M (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - N-R (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - S (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - T-Y (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Subseries P. Texas II, 1949-1950
    Includes correspondence, minutes, bulletins, programs, bills, outlines, lists, postcards, news clippings, telegrams.
    - A (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - B-D (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - F-G (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - H-L (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - M-P (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - S (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - T-W (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Subseries Q. Urbana, 1953-1954
    Includes correspondence,papers, contents, report, list notes, statement.
    - A (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - B-G (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - L-R (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - S (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - T-W (Box 8, Folder 38)
- Series V. Notes and printed materials, 1901-1953
  Includes correspondence, bibliographic notes, pamphlets, programs, certificates, news clippings.
  - Gynasium zu Gotha - graduation programs, 1901-1902 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Lecture Notes, July 1902 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Lecture Notes, 1902 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Lecture Notes, c. 1902 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Bermudo-Biblio. Notes, c.1902-1906 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Lecture Notes, Aug. 1902-Jan. 1903 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Lecture Notes, May 1903-July 1903 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Lecture Notes, Oct. 1903-Dec. 1903 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Lecture Notes, Oct. 1903-Jan. 1904 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Lecture Notes, Oct. 1903-Mar. 1904 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Notes - Composition, 1903 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Notes - Bermudo and Sancta Maria, c. 1903 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Notes - Mozart, 1903-1904 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Catalog - British Museum and others (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Berlin KGL Biblio. Call Slips, 1904-1908 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Lecture Notes, Jan. 1904-Mar. 1904 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Lecture Notes, Music of the Middle Ages, Apr. 1904-June 1904 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Lecture Notes, Schubert to Brahms, May 1904-July 1904 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Lecture Notes, Kant's Philosophy, May 1904-July 1904 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Lecture Notes, History of the Symphany, May 1904-Aug. 1904 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Lecture Notes, Old Music, 1904 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Lecture Notes, Music History of the 16th and 17th Centuries, England (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Lecture Notes, History of Music in Italy (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Notes on Kontrapundt, Oct. 1905 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Lecture Notes, History of Opera, 1905 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Lecture Notes, c. 1905 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Bibliographic Notes, c. 1906 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Bibliographic Notes, c. 1906-1907 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Bibliographic Notes, 1906-1907 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Bibliographic Notes, 1906-1907 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Bibliographic Notes, 1907 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Bibliographic Notes, and list of organists at Langewiesen, 1907 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Bibliographies, c. 1907-1909 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Bibliographies, c. 1907 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Lecture Notes - Breslau, Summer, 1911 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Lecture VI, Jan. 19, 1910 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Lecture Notes, Summer Semester, 1913 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Lecture Notes, Winter Semester, 1913-1914 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Lecture Notes, History of Symphany, Jan. 8, 1910 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Lecture Notes, Summer Semester, 1910 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Lecture Notes, Palestrina and Bach, 1910 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Lecture Notes, Winter Semester - History of Song, 1911-1912 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Lecture Notes, Brahms, Oct. 28, 1913 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Lecture Notes, Opera Lecture, May 1910-June 1910 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Lecture Notes, July 5, 1910 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Lecture Notes, July 5, 1910 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Biographical Notes, Folk Song, c. 1910 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Erlebach Notes, c. 1910 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Biographical Notes, c. 1910 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Lecture Notes, Beethoven, 1911 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Bibliography, Breslau, c. 1909-1914 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Lecture Notes, History of Choir Music; 1911, 1913 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Biographical and Lecture Notes; 1912-1913 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Bibliographic Notes before 1914 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Bibliographic Notes on Songs before 1914 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Bibliographic Notes before 1914 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Bibliographic Notes, 1914 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Introduction to Alexander Wheelock Thayer's Life of Beethoven, 1914 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Dr. Escher, Zurich, on libraries, 1918-1920 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Bibliographic Notes, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - List of books ordered for New York Public Library, May 5, 1922 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - European Trip - hotel bills; 1921-1922 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - from Dr. Ercdmann, "The Crisis of the Small Theatre," 1922 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - from Dr. Ercdmann on the Berlin Theatre, 1922 (Box 11, Folder 13)